EMIL LAMPRECHT: Now I'm going to show you the first snatch trick.
Now, this trick has a lot of different things going on.
So, it may take a while to get your first successful snatch especially with an even and straight box.
Snatch looks like this.
Now, the things that are involved in the snatch.
First of all, a very even upward release is important.
If the box is kind of all over the place, first of all, you won't be able to snatch the middle box and second of all, it will be very hard to have the center box travel properly towards the center or you can then snatch it or reclamp it.
Also, we're using some of the dynamic of the push and pull that I showed you in the separations to push the box you're releasing over this direction.
Then, of course, you have to catch in a snatch-like way the center box out from everything else without screwing up the pressure on the other boxes.
It's a very dynamic trick.
It takes a lot of practice but it's pretty cool in my opinion.
Obviously, you want to be able to do it on both sides.
You'll usually find that your nondominant hand will have a harder time with an even release but some practice will get it there.
Being able to do it--being able to do it back and forth is very beneficial to developing a routine.